<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BLOG</title>
        <link>/</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 09:43:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Social Media for Businesses: A Beginner’s Guide]]></title>
            <link>/posts/2021-04-08/social-media-for-businesses-a-beginners-guide</link>
            <guid>/posts/2021-04-08/social-media-for-businesses-a-beginners-guide</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="document_Welcome__3Zgd2"><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-1.712acef5.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>There was a time when social media websites like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Whatsapp, etc. were purely utilized for connecting people online, sharing information and ideas globally. But now, in recent times, their usage is not not only limited to facilitate social connections but people are now using it to grow their business connections as well.</p><p>Changing times and the recent worldwide pandemic have changed the dynamics of the businesses that were operating traditionally. Hence social media platforms have helped people in promotion, branding, and scaling the growth of their business. Let us look at some ways how your business can benefit from social media web websites.</p><h2 id="1-helps-in-creating-your-digital-presence">1. Helps in creating your digital presence.</h2><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-2.b25e52ca.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>Creating business accounts/pages/groups on these social media websites build a digital identity for your businesses.</p><h2 id="2-make-your-business-more-reachable-to-the-targetted-audience">2. Make your business more reachable to the targetted audience</h2><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-3.5015a3a7.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>With the help of their digital business tools, SEOs, it helps you to reach out to your target audience easily.</p><h2 id="3-marketing-and-promotion-of-your-products-and-content">3. Marketing and promotion of your products and content</h2><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-4.417eb04f.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>Easy and affordable means of promotion of your content or products through influencers, user’s reviews, and recommendations online</p><h2 id="4-generates-new-leads-and-customers">4. Generates new leads and customers</h2><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-5.5a8c2d49.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>Your content reaches out to a wider range of audiences that help them to connect and experience your services at ease.</p><h2 id="5-boost-your-sales-and-growth-of-your-business">5. Boost your sales and growth of your business</h2><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-6.899769b2.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>As the number of people using social media increases, there will be an increase in new customers which will eventually aid in the growth of your business</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI-UX : Beginner’s Guide; Part 1]]></title>
            <link>/posts/2021-04-08/ui-ux-beginners-guide-part-1</link>
            <guid>/posts/2021-04-08/ui-ux-beginners-guide-part-1</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="document_Welcome__3Zgd2"><p>What is UI UX? Why are we hearing it so much around the streets of tech
advanced areas? Is it some new slang? Are the people using it trying to look cool
or does it actually mean something ? When you read UI\UX, what comes to your
mind? What is it? Where did it come from? How did it become such a huge topic
of interest?</p><p>Well, to answer your question, UI is User Interface and UX is User Experience.
To simplify it even more, anything that you see on a screen- whether it is your
phone, tab, laptop or pc, is UI and, what you go through, while using it, is UX.</p><p>Essentially, UX applies to anything that can be experienced- be it a website, a
coffee machine, or a visit to the supermarket. The “user experience” part refers to
the interaction between the user and a product or service.</p><p>While user experience is a compilaiton of tasks focused on the optimization of a
product for effective and enjoyable use, user interface design is its complement;
the look and feel, the presentation and interactivity of a product.</p><p>The UI of any device or website or app revolves arround providing the subject a
good UX in order to keep them hooked and leave them wanting more. All the
background work that goes on while designing a product that is a perfect fit for
the customer includes UI UX design.</p><p>It’s important to understand that UX and UI do go hand-in-hand; you can’t have
one without the other. However, you don’t need to possess UI design skills to be a
UX designer, and vice versa.</p><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-1.88336a28.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div><p>If you think about a house, it begins with the decision to start builing a place for
yourself, to live breathe and spend your life in. Similarly, the design of any
product starts with an idea. The idea about what is the product.</p><p>Next comes the stage of designing, You spend hours browsing catalogues,
websites, from one architect to another until you find the one designer, who you
trust, will solve all your issues and fulfill all your needs.
In a kinda similar way, afters hours and hours of sole searching, you arrive at an
idea that this is the product we’re going to make, it will slve so and so issues and it
will be so and so workable.</p><p>Just like architects use a blueprint to construct every part of a house, from
physical structures to more complex workings drawings like electrical and
plumbing, UI UX design describes the hierarchy, navigation, features, and
interactions of a website or application.</p><p>And just as blueprints are the most valuable document for an architect to use in
the construction of a building, UI UX design can be the most powerful tool to
make an efficient and workable product.</p><p>And just as blueprints are the most valuable document for an architect to use in
the construction of a building, UI UX design can be the most powerful tool to
make an efficient and workable product.</p><ul><li>framework</li><li>research</li><li>analysis</li><li>arrangement</li><li>designing</li><li>prototyping</li><li>development</li><li>compiling the data</li><li>background research</li><li>designing some more</li><li>usability testing</li><li>designing the product</li><li>execution</li><li>deployment</li><li>and the work goes on</li></ul><p>After all this work, the product that arrives in the digital marketplace is the MVP
i.e., Minimal Viable Product.</p><p>But the work is not finished yet. This MVP is the basic prototype, Which will
engage the users and invite their reviews and feedbacks, and again, the work will
start from square one, although this time with a little less background work.</p><p>Hence, UI UX is a vast spread industry, which is growing everyday with new
advancements and since there are no user guides or philosophies, everyone can
conceptualise one of their own, whatever suits their needs.</p><p>To conclude, UI UX design is a conversation. This conversation happens between
a machine and a person who uses it. When people interact with a product, they
love having smooth interactions, but it only happens when UI UX designers make
things right.</p><p>Also, watch this space to learn what’s next !</p><div class="document_img-wrapper__2otJM"><img src="/static/media/image-2.db4b76ad.jpg" class="img-fluid"/></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>